<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home of Geoffrey Liu on PS70: Intro to Digital Fabrication</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/</link><description>Recent content in Home of Geoffrey Liu on PS70: Intro to Digital Fabrication</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week 10+ (Final Project) Updates</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_10/</guid><description>My final project is creating a Chat-GPT (or another large LLM) powered Tamagochi. There will be different characters that you can upload to the tamagochi, and you can talk to them using voice, and it will respond back using either actions, text and voice. The idea is that the Tamagochi pet can act as a friend, teacher, pet, or anything you can dream of as long as you can prompt ChatGPT to do something.</description></item><item><title>Week 9: Networking</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_9/</guid><description>This week we wanted to recreate laser-tag using laser-pointers and photo-receivers. This didn&amp;rsquo;t work too well, so we ended up using infrared (IR) LED&amp;rsquo;s and IR photo-transistors instead.
I worked with Isaac and David on this project, and we split up the work into multiple parts:
Web-app Electronic circuit Sensors Physical design In my documentation I will focus on the parts that I understand the most: the web-app, setting up firebase, and the sensor.</description></item><item><title>Week 8: CNC Milling, Molding &amp; Casting</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_8/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted ice-cubes in the shape of mountain ranges* After some quick research I found this abomination of a &amp;lsquo;Mount Fuji&amp;rsquo; ice-mold.
And a better one of Mount Everest that was $97. So this week I&amp;rsquo;m developing a process of making mountain-range ice-molds using CNC, 3D printing (unfortunately as CNC&amp;rsquo;s didn&amp;rsquo;t work out), and silicone molds.
Making mountain ice/chocolate/plaster-molds Attempt 1: CNC Milling the negative To 3D-model the mountain range, I first had to find some software or program that could give me some sort of an elevation map.</description></item><item><title>Week 7: Electronic Output Devices</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_7/</guid><description>This week I was humbled by simple electronics.
I decided to play around with speakers and microphones this week. This article will be a diary of how I was humbled by simple electronics&amp;hellip;
Idea 1: Audio recording and playback My first idea was to create a speech recorder that played back on a speaker using the parts we had in the lab. The first step is to get the microphone working.</description></item><item><title>3D Design &amp; Printing</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_5/</guid><description>This weeks task is to design and print a 3D object that cannot be easily created using subtractive methods. I decided to design a Klein Bottle and a Torus. For reference, a Klein bottle can be loosely thought of as a &amp;lsquo;3D mobius strip&amp;rsquo; and a Torus is essentially a donut. They&amp;rsquo;re both interesting mathematical objects and also very hard to create using subtractive methods. I used Fusion360 to design the Klein Bottle and MeshLab to design the torus.</description></item><item><title>Week 6: Electronic Input Devices</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_6/</guid><description>We covered various types of capacitive sensors this week, I use charged copper sheets to create my own water-level sensor and also tacked 3D positoning using an the MPU6050.
Items MPU6050 (or another 6-9 axis IMU) Breadboard ESP32 Wires 3D positioning with the MPU6050 At the start of the week, I thought a great idea would be to get a 3D positioning. The idea is that I could use the acceleration and gyroscope readings from the MPU6050, apply some fancy filters and data-processing to somehow get a more accurate reading, and double-integrate the processed acceleration values to obtain the 3D displacement.</description></item><item><title>Week 4: Microcontroller programming</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_4/</guid><description>This week I created the first iteration of my automatic plant watering system using a moisture sensor, water pump and OLED display. There were three main components to this project:
Connecting the components to the microcontroller Calibrating the moisture sensor Make other components do stuff based on moisture sensor data List of components ESP32-S2 DevKitC Push button 10k resistor Breadboard Wires 5V water pump L9110 motor driver LED Capacitive Soil Moisture Sensor 128x64px OLED display (I2C) Connecting the components The push button was attached using a pulldown resistor using the instructions found here .</description></item><item><title>Week 3: Hand tools and fabrication</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_3/</guid><description>Kinetic sculptures While researching different types of kinetic sculptures, I was really intrigued by wire sculptures. The thin lines are really elegant and I like how objects connected to the wires move.
These types of sculptures reminded my of a Hills Hoist , typically found in Australia and is used to hang dry clothes (dryers are alot less common there), it spins around when it&amp;rsquo;s windy and also a fundamental instrument in Australian university culture.</description></item><item><title>Final Project</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/final_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/final_project/</guid><description>I have two ideas
PassioGo Tracker Inspired by MBTA tracker.
I came across this website TrainTrackr from a FB ad which tracks the MBTA trains in real time. I thought it would be cool to make a similar website for the Harvard Shuttle&amp;rsquo;s on PassioGo since the app is so bad.
Hydroponic Indoor Herb Greenhouse I love cooking, and my number one biggest pet peeve is having to go to the grocery store to buy fresh herbs.</description></item><item><title>Week 2: 2D Design &amp; Cutting</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_2/</guid><description>I was on the waitlist for the class and joined 1.5 weeks late so my documentation starts on Week 2 :). This week, I worked on:
developing the website to document my progress throughout the course Working on 2D design and laser printing using Fusion360 Website creation I have pretty much no experience in front-end web development, most of my skills are in backend development and database stuff. I chose to develop this website using Hugo.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/page/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/page/about/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Geoff. I&amp;rsquo;m a graduate student from Australia studying Computer Science at Harvard SEAS, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in machine learning, startups and quite recently systems design and engineering. I enjoy nature photography, hiking, cooking and over-engineered products.
Some images from my hiking trips</description></item></channel></rss>