<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on PS70: Intro to Digital Fabrication</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on PS70: Intro to Digital Fabrication</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week 3: Hand tools and fabrication</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_3/</guid><description>Kinetic sculptures While researching different types of kinetic sculptures, I was really intrigued by wire sculptures. The thin lines are really elegant and I like how objects connected to the wires move.
These types of sculptures reminded my of a Hills Hoist , typically found in Australia and is used to hang dry clothes (dryers are alot less common there), it spins around when it&amp;rsquo;s windy and also a fundamental instrument in Australian university culture.</description></item><item><title>Final Project</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/final_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/final_project/</guid><description>I have two ideas
PassioGo Tracker Inspired by MBTA tracker.
I came across this website TrainTrackr from a FB ad which tracks the MBTA trains in real time. I thought it would be cool to make a similar website for the Harvard Shuttle&amp;rsquo;s on PassioGo since the app is so bad.
Hydroponic Indoor Herb Greenhouse I love cooking, and my number one biggest pet peeve is having to go to the grocery store to buy fresh herbs.</description></item><item><title>Week 2: 2D Design &amp; Cutting</title><link>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geometrikz.github.io/PS70/blog/week_2/</guid><description>I was on the waitlist for the class and joined 1.5 weeks late so my documentation starts on Week 2 :). This week, I worked on:
developing the website to document my progress throughout the course Working on 2D design and laser printing using Fusion360 Website creation I have pretty much no experience in front-end web development, most of my skills are in backend development and database stuff. I chose to develop this website using Hugo.</description></item></channel></rss>